The Clarion Records, 1966-2013 (bulk 1982-1986)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
The Clarion Records, 1966-2013 (bulk 1982-1986)
MS 534
The Clarion
The Clarion Records, 1966-2013 (bulk 1982-1986), includes financial papers, administrative papers, and newspaper issues from The Clarion Newspaper. The Clarion newspaper was a Tucson based newspaper that focused on women’s issues. Items in the collection include tax documents, newspaper clippings, newspaper issues, staff files, and subscription information.
2 Linear Feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
No Restrictions
Historical Note
The Clarion newspaper began in 1976 as a newsletter for the Tucson Women’s Commission. The Tucson Women’s Commission is a city agency dedicated to the elimination of sexual discrimination and the achievement equality of opportunity for women. In 1981 The Clarion was incorporated as a non-profit organization with the support of Tucson’s major and council and in 1982 The Clarion became an independent community based newspaper. The Clarion focused on and promoted a clearer understanding of issues and events effecting women’s health, employment, children, politics, arts, and interpersonal relationships. In 2013 the Tucson Women’s Commission initiated a newsletter named Clarion Redux
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 3 series
Series I: Administrative Files,
Series II: Newspaper Issues,
Series III: Financial Records,
Scope and Content Note
Papers 1966-2013 (bulk 1982-1986): This collection consists of administrative files, financial records, and newspaper issues. The bulk of the material consists of subscription and distribution lists, newspaper issues and advertising documents. Administrative files include material related to the staff including resumes, resignations, memos and classified ads as well as materials related to the organizational history, subscriptions and distributions, various board meetings and the salute awards. The financial records include tax and financial information, fundraising activities and grant foundations. Also included are The Clarion newspaper issues.
Access Terms
Women's Issues
Women--Newspapers
Newspapers--20th Century
Tucson(Ariz,).
Container List
- Series 1: Administrative Files, 1966-2013
  This series contains materials pertaining to the management of The Clarion and relationships with related agencies. Information about newspaper distribution and subscriptions, meetings and events, administrative boards, advertising and promotion, organizational history, publication, and staff is included. Also included are news clippings related to women’s issues and The Clarion. The materials are arranged alphabetically.
  - Advertising, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Advertising - Betty Lewis, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clarion Boards, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clarion Organization, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Distribution, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Meetings, 1982-1986, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - News Clippings, 1966, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Promotional Material, 1977, 1981, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Publishing, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Salute Awards, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Staff, 1981-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Subscriptions, circa 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Subscriptions (1 of 2), circa 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Subscriptions (2 of 2), circa 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Tucson Women's Commission, 2010, 2012, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Women's Issues, 1982, 1983, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - YWCA, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Clarion, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Series 2: Newspaper Issues, 1982-2013
  This series contains issues of The Clarion newspaper. The issues are original copies of The Clarion. In 2013 the Tucson Women’s Commission initiated The Clarion Redux.
  - The Clarion, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Clarion (1 of 2), 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Clarion (2 of 2), 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Clarion, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Clarion, 1986-2013 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series 3: Financial Records, 1981-1988
  This series contains financial records produced by The Clarion. These records include bank statements, financial reports, insurance, and tax documents. Also included are materials related to foundations The Clarion solicited for information about grants.
  - Bank Statements, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Finance Reports, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Fundraising, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Gannet Foundation, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Grant Foundation, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Insurance, 1982,1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Taxes, 1981-1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)